CURRICULUM VITAE

Steven Dow

Freelance Creative

I'm an Art director, Visual designer and UI/UX designer from Amsterdam. I have more then 15 years experience and I have designed online and offline for brands in the top 100 at both agency and client side.

I enjoy working on BIG and small projects developing concepts, designing web sites, user interfaces for web and smartphone applications, and online and offline campaigns, with the goal, providing innovative ideas and designs that solve problems, between businesses and their customers.

Portfolio

www.steezie.nl

My approach to design doesn't end at making stunning visuals, I also focus on the experience and function of my designs. Great design is not purely based on how it looks, it's a combination of stunning visuals, great experience and simplicity. I believe strongly that great design is in the small details.

Clients

ARA, BrandBase, Bureau aan de Amstel, DMO, Deutsche Telekom, Eigenfabrikaat, JUNIOR* academie for advertising, Media Republic, New Message, TomTom, Tommy Hilfiger, YoungWorks, Vodafone and Y&R.

Albert Heijn, ABN AMRO, Deutsche Telekom, ING, KLM, Land Rover, Levi's, Nuon, Nike, Pampers, TomTom, Tommy Hilfiger, UPC, United Emirates. Vodafone, VW, WWF, Wrangler and more ...

Super Powers

ART DIRECTION

CONCEPT DEVELOPMENT

WORK EXPERIENCE

August 2006 - present

Position **Duties**

: Steezie your design hero

: Freelance Art director | visual designer | UX designer

Working for various agencies and clients designing smartphone and/or web applications, websites, and online

and off line campaigns onsite or offsite.

May 2013 - October 2013

Position **Duties**

: Vodafone

Freelance Art director I visual designer

Working for the Vodafone Group R&D automotive team at the Vodafone campus in Dusseldorf. Working closely together with the UX designer and the agile development team. Responsible for creating concepts, prototypes

and GUI's for the Vodafone Xone beta product IOS6 & IOS7 and Android automotive product.

March 2013 - May 2013

Position **Duties**

: Deutsche Telekom

: Freelance Art director | Visual designer

Working for the product design team at the head office in Bonn. Working closely together with the Senior Product Designer and visual designer, responsible for creating concepts, prototypes and GUI's for future

Telekom products with the main focus of improving Telekom experience on mobile devices.

May 2012 - November 2012

Position **Duties**

: TomTom

Freelance Art director | Visual designer

Working alongside the UX designer, interaction designer and developers focused on the core navigation software. Responsible for producing design concepts, executing designs based on established style guides and updating the style guides and developing detailed design specs for production for web, desktop

and navigation device applications.

October 2010 - March 2011

Position Duties

: strawberryfrog

: Senior designer

: Responsible for producing graphical productions of website, microsites, EDM's, banners and landing pages, typography of texts, the precise use of the branding, monitoring and where necessary recommend the use concerning the branding and other duties.

December 2009 - November 2011

Position **Duties:**

: eBuddy

Visual Designer

Working as a core member and a primary point of contact on visual design matters of the Products and Marketing Team. Responsible for the visual appearance of the eBuddy web and mobile products, developing and guarding a consistent eBuddy branding both online & offline, creating resources for the GUI's of the existing Web (AJAX) and Mobile (J2ME, iPhone and Android). Creating the most optimal, strong and effective designs that enhance both the visual appearance and interactive behaviour of the eBuddy products in every detail.

January 2009 - February 2011

Position Duties: : Junior Academie voor Art Direction

: Teacher

I was responsible for teaching and developing the teaching program for the field Desktop Publishing for the first and second year. Within 2 years, students are trained as junior desktop publisher. The program teaches the student how to work with the Adobe CS programs Indesign, Illustrator and Photoshop. The teaching program consists of image editing, typography, image processing, vector and pixel illustrations, graphic design, layout and more. All these skills are combined in graphic design assignments which are increased in difficulty in each assignment.

February 2008 - June 2008

Position Duties : Roorda Reclamebureau

Designer I desktop publisher

Responsible for: coordinating the Desktop Publishers and the activities in the studio. Producing graphical productions for print and web, typography of texts, Photoshop retouching, the precise use of the branding, monitoring and where necessary recommend the use concerning the branding. Goal: producing production ready files, proof prints, certified PDFs and other duties.

August 2007 - January 2008

Position Duties : TBWA

: Designer I desktop publisher

Responsible for producing graphical productions for the Albert Heijn BONUS booklet, typography of texts, the precise use of the branding, monitoring and where necessary recommend the use concerning the branding and other duties.

January 2006 - June 2006

Position Duties : Found

: Designer I desktop publisher

: Responsible for producing graphical productions of in-store marketing material (including POS), adverts for Nike stores in Europe and Asia with the goal: producing production ready files, proof prints, certified PDFs and other duties.

October 2004 - October 2006

Position Duties : Wiliams Lea

Designer I desktop publisher

Working at a client location (unit), responsible for producing graphical productions, typography of texts, the precise use of the branding, monitoring and where necessary recommend the use concerning the branding for presentations for on- screen and/or pitch books. Goal: producing proof prints, digital prints and other duties.

2002 – 2003 : Working holiday in Australia

2000 – 2002 Position Duties : Intergrafipak: Desktop publisher

: Responsible for the development and adjustment of designs for various packaging, inserts and labels and/or client delivered designs (on both Mac and PC). Goal: producing proof prints, colour separations, film for plate

production, digital proofs and other duties.

EDUCATION / COURSES

2012 : Junior Academie for Advertising, Bachelor of Arts (BA).
Successfully completed Art direction, Desktop publishing and Graphic design education.

2001 : Grafisch Media Instituut Amsterdam
Vocational Education
Successfully completed Adobe Illustrator and Quark Xpress Basic Training Course.

2000 : Grafisch Media Instituut Amsterdam
Vocational Education
Successfully completed Adobe Illustrator and Quark Xpress Advanced Training Course.

1999 : IBM Professional Certification Program Boulder - Colorado America
University of Professional Education

Successfully completed the IBM InfoColor 70 Operations Training Course.

1999	: Xerox Education Centre Vocational Education Successfully completed the Xerox Docutech 6135/80 Operator Training Courses
1998	: Xerox Education Centre Vocational Education Successfully completed the DigiPath 1.1 Training Courses
1998	: Grafisch Lyceum Amsterdam Media Design Successfully completed Media Design

1997 : Grafisch Lyceum Amsterdam Graphic Design Successfully completed Graphic Arts

SOFTWARE:

Mac OS and Windows: Axure, Flash, Illustrator, InDesign, Sublime Text 2, and Photoshop.

LANGUAGES:

English and Dutch (bilingual) and German limited working proficiency.

REFERENCES:



Fabian Nehne

Head of Hardware Design (VP) at Deutsche Telekom

I got to know Steven as a very ingenious UI-concepter and an amazingly fast visual designer. Also he is a great guy to have in the team.



Guido Gehlen

Principal Expert Automotive at Vodafone Group Services GmbH

"Steven jumped into our project as visual designer on short notice and delivered with vast speed and professionalism the smartphone app designs for Vodafone's brand new XONE beta product drivexone. He did the art direction of the iPhone and Android apps and guided three designers. Steven did an excellent job and became an essential part of the agile development team. "



Lennart Hennigs

Senior Interaction Designer bei Deutsche Telekom

"Steven was a great addition to our team. He is a seasoned designer with a good eye for effective design solutions. He always delivered high quality work on time and all his concepts were well thought through. It was a pleasure to work with him."



Joost de Vries

CloseAlert

"Steven did an important website redesign for our company and helped us in the process of content decisions. Furthermore, we could provide him with quite a high-level briefing and still get excellent results without too many feedback loops."

More references on request.